start with a cube with side length one
over square root 1. on top of that place
a cube with side length one over square
root of two on top of that place a cube
with the side length of 1 over the
square root of three and continue this
process indefinitely the resulting
structure sometimes called the infinite
GIF consists of an infinite stack of
Cubes each with a side length of 1 over
the square root of n each Cube has a
side with area given by the square root
of one over N squared so the total
surface area of this structure is
greater than or equal to four times the
infinite sum where n ranges from 1 to
Infinity of 1 over root N squared on the
other hand the volume of each cube is
given by the quantity one over the
square root of n cubed so the volume of
this structure is the infinite sum where
n ranges from 1 to Infinity of the
quantity one over root n cubed it turns
out that the area series diverges
because it's the harmonic series times
four and the volume infinite series
converges to a value that's
approximately 2.61 this structure is a
discrete version of Gabriel's horn and
can be used for the painter's paradox